Jesper Kjeldgaard



thejspr@gmail.com
Aarhus. Denmark

For the past 10 years, I have worked with full-stack development in several startups and companies, mostly revolving around Ruby on Rails. Latest as a senior software engineer at Peanut, building APIs for scaling a social network for women. Before that as CTO and co-founder building a platform for ordering and delivering graphic designs.

My drive comes from delivering value to the business, and I love being part of solving problems from initial ideas to deployment. Besides having solid experience in building web-applications, I also have experience with marketing automation, finance, analytics, mobile development and leading small teams.

Experience

Peanut, Senior Software Engineer

2019-present

Working on backend and back-office tools for a social network for women.

Grafik on Demand, Co-founder and CTO

2017 - 2019

Built a web-application for ordering and delivering graphic designs online. I built the platform and marketing site, as well as a range of marketing automation integrations. Technologies used are Rails, React, Sass, Webpack, Bootstrap and Postgresql.

Webyard (Owner), Software Consultant

2015 - 2017

Working with Android, Ruby, Rails and other web technologies for several clients including include <u>Skyscanner</u> (travel), <u>Bitsilk</u> (agency) and <u>GoMore</u> (social car-sharing and rental).

HouseTrip, Software Engineer

2013 - 2014

Working on a large Rails application with many moving parts. I was involved in several big projects like; a responsive redesign of several key pages, introducing feature flags, migrating our CI to TravisCI and other initiatives to improve conversion rates. I was also a lead engineer in a team of 5.

Evently, Software Engineer.

2011 - 2013

At Evently I worked on making online event-marketing easier. This includes adding features to and maintaining a large Rails application, and building new APIs.

Education

MSc. Internet Application Development.

2010 - 2011

Middlesex University, London, United Kingdom.

BSc. Software Engineering.

2007 - 2010

Aalborg University, Denmark.

Links

Blog: <u>thejspr.com</u>

Github: github.com/thejspr

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/jesperkjeldgaard